# mohamed mahmoud

Email:

mohammed\_hs55@yahoo.com

### Back End Developer (Laravel/VueJs)

I'm a Self-Taught Full-Stack Web Developer who prefers to work as a Back-end Developer,

I have been in the web development field for more than 4 years, got my first project 3 years ago, decided to focus on back-end development especially for Laravel and Vuejs 3 year ago after learning a lot of web technology in backend as well as frontend.

now I'm familiar with many web technologies like Python, nodejs, c++, but specialized in Laravel, Vuejs, and their sidekicks

**EXPERIENCE** 

Feb 2019 to Present

## **Back End Developer**

**iVAS** 

• Write clean, secure, test driven, easily maintainable and modular code and use some design pattern

to increase project performance and to make project easy scalable. • Troubleshoot and debug applications. • Act as technical lead in some project in the last 5 month. • Perform UI / backend tests to optimize performance. • Collaborate and work with frontend and mobile app developers on the backend needs of projects. • Collaborate with team

• Client communication (verbal/written) as and when required • Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services API • Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and post launch support

**Grand** Jun 2018 to Oct 2018

### **Full Time Back End Developer**

 Client communication (verbal/written) as and when required • Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services API • Collaborate and work with frontend and mobile app developers on the backend needs of projects. • Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and post launch support

# **LoadServ For Integrated Business Solution**

Jan 2018 to May 2018

### Full Time Back End Developer

• Collaborate and work with a team and develop myself to learn new technical. • Help team to solve complex problem and collaborate with them. • In some project take front end problem and work in it to improve my self in front end technology • Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and post launch support

# Faggala Start Up, Smart Villages

Aug 2017 to Sep 2017

### **Training Back End Developer**

• Learn how to work with Agile methods especially with scrum • Learn how to work with OpenCart Cms to make system • Learn how to search and how to be self-study

Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder

### Innova Egypt

Intern

• Innova is a leader in transforming Revolutionary ideas into products and quickly adopted in your

home and office • Designing and developing innovative products and systems to improve the quality of life both in

corporate buildings and residential • Learn how to make your startup and the lifecycle for taking your product to Light

**EDUCATION** 

# **Helwan University Cairo**

2014 to 2018

Bachelor's degree

**SKILLS** 

Laravel, Vue.js, MongoDB, Data Structures, Software Development, Algorithms, C++, php, JavaScript, HTML5, MySQL, jQuery, Python, C, Linux, Git, Node.js, Teamwork, Team Building, Problem Solving, Software System Analysis, Software Design Patterns, Heroku, Redis

**PROJECTS** 

LVEH Oct 2019 to Present

### https://multivue.herokuapp.com

Building a complete Admin panel for the e-commerce system using the vuejs as well as laravel has some beautiful properties as well as a simplified UI for ease of use to become a different and beautiful Admin panel

- Building ui for dashboard with vuejs and vuex as oop for vuejs
- Using laravel for make adminpanel with Repository design pattern
- Dynamic added language for dashboard for Translation

Insurance

May 2020 to Jun 2020

#### https://insurence.herokuapp.com

Insurance is a mobile application to help people in the medical sector that is used by the client to display prescription, and one of the doctors follows up on the prescription, to find treatment details and help the customer get it.

- Using laravel for make admin panel with Repository design pattern
- Using vuejs for some module like notification and chatting
- Make real-time chat, notification with pusher and make push notification with firebase
- Have some feature like, role & permission, display reporting graph

# missed-people

Jan 2019 to Mar 2019

### https://missed-gb.herokuapp.com

It is a system to search for kidnapped children by recognizing their forms through analyzing pictures and finding similarities between them as well as different ages. Artificial intelligence was used to solve this problem, and the system was made as a social media for easy communication with people and getting acquainted with the kidnapped.sytem build with

Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder

laravel and python

- Using laravel for make admin panel with Repository design pattern
- Using vuejs for some module like notification and chatting, added post, comments
- · Make real-time chat, notification with pusher and make push notification with firebase
- Using flask as a python web framework to make API for compare images with facedetection

package

**Autevo** 

Apr 2020 to Jun 2020

### https://autevo-car.herokuapp.com

It is a car wash system by connecting the driver with the customer who wants to wash, the system can handle the washing time and distribute the washers automatically to the drivers

## **Greeting\_vuejs**

*Apr 2020 to Jun 2020* 

### https://greetingnew.ivascloud.com

It is a web application to help the user to create a video clip by merging the images with the sound, and he can select a picture or sound by category from our side or upload his picture and voice, and he can write on the picture and the system has other good features

- Using laravel for make admin panel that have nice feature
- Using vuejs for make module that help to create awesome videos or images
- Using FFmpeg for helping us to make these videos and images

Mondia

May 2020 to Jun 2020

### https://islamic.digizone.com.kw

It is a web application to help a Muslim hear the Qur'an from his favorite Sheikh, and he has some features such as knowing the nearest mosque, knowing the time of prayer, calculating inheritance, knowing the direction of the qiblah and some other good features you can using service by subscription with our operators like du-emirate and omentel

#### Ratatouille

Ian 2018 to Mar 2018

#### https://me-me.herokuapp.com

It is a website like Facebook you can from it make a post, comments, likes, add friends, make group, chatting, you can log in with Gmail account or your Facebook account

## Aghezty

May 2020 to Jul 2020

### https://aghezty.com

Aghezty is a website for sale through which you can buy home and mobile devices and it is full of electrical devices. It contains a wonderful filter through which you can search for what you want as well as on a control panel through which you can control all parts of the site you can purchase by credit card or payment in cash.

# **BodyTalk**

Apr 2020 to Jun 2020

http://bodytalk.digizone.com.kw

It is a web app through which you can learn how to deal with people as well as know the movements of the body and what it means, as well as how to address pets and know what signs mean The site is presented in Arabic as well as English as well as added the dark mode

Present Cima http://cima-cima.herokuapp.com Present whatsapp https://whatsapp.digizone.com.kw Present HamedZaid Website https://hamedzaid.com/sub\_cat/13 Present. Alfacy Webapp https://dev.digizone.com.kw/alafasy web app v **3\_php7** Present HamedZaid WebApp https://ivascloud.com/hamed\_zaid\_web\_app\_ba ckend/ Present Masrah Masr https://ivascloud.com/masrah\_masr/ Present. Nour Khaled https://ivascloud.com/nour\_khatab/

Afshat Aflam

Present

https://ivascloud.com/afshat\_aflam/

# **Joop Android App**

Jul 2018 to Oct 2018

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.joobdriver&hl=en

This Project Like Uber But It,s For Shipping goods To People, More details For Prjoct After Use It RealTime Connect Application offices And Driver With Customer To Shipping goods The application of Joop Driver is an application for drivers, Helped transport people and the things they needed. Leadership whenever you want - no offices or presidents. Wherever you want to go, we want you to enjoy the trip and the destination Register for driving within the Joop Driver application. We'll walk you through the steps and notify you when you're ready to

drive. working In Back End For this Project With Laravel, Vue Js and Sql

### Dr Wash android App

Jun 2018 to Aug 2018

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.drwash&hl=en

This Project For Washing Cars , Building , Boat , Houses ans Some Category Else RealTime Connect Delegate With Customer To Deliver And Washing What he Want Dr. Wash is the easiest and quickest way to book cleaning services for car carpets and steam houses, cleaning boats and roofs of buildings and offers the best offers and prices. assign Order To Delegate With RealTime FireBase Notification After That Told Customer who Delegate That Assign For His Order Working In Back End With Laravel , Ajax For Assign Order

# **Taalaky IOS App**

Jun 2018 to Aug 2018

https://itunes.apple.com/eg/app/taalaky/id1407 358084?mt=8&ign-mpt=uo%3D4

Application taalaky offers a unique collection of designers that offer the best designs at the best prices, from which you can easily buy and get the right design for your taste. Working In Back End With Laravel, RealTime Notification With FireBase

Pizza Present

https://pizzahero.herokuapp.com

### **Elgallad-Group**

Present

https://elgallad-group.com.eg

**Kidz** Present

https://kids.ivascloud.com

**GYM** Present

https://gym.ivascloud.com

Flatter Present

https://flatter.ivascloud.com/

# yummy-food-vuejs

Sep 2018 to Dec 2018

https://yummy-food-vuejs.herokuapp.com

E-commerce website for food build with laravel & vuejs used mongodb as database system for this project

1 4410114050

LANGUAGES

**Arabic** (Native or bilingual proficiency), **English** (Professional working proficiency)

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

CCNA

*Apr 2015*